<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Exhibition on Charisse</title><link>https://charissefoo.me/tags/exhibition/</link><description>Recent content in Exhibition on Charisse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charissefoo.me/tags/exhibition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Satellite Town</title><link>https://charissefoo.me/blog/satellite-town/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.me/blog/satellite-town/</guid><description>Satellite Town illustrates a future of ecological living beyond the limits of the Earth. In a research community living in a satellite orbiting the Moon, distinct notions of self-sufficiency and sustainability are explored, each with a distinct color palette. The Forest depicts the distinctive pink glow of high intensity LEDs for crop growth; The Street imagines an underpass with bioluminescent mycelium pavements that generate electricity from footsteps; The Chapel depicts a zero-gravity projection room featuring an endless sunset against distant planets.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Memory</title><link>https://charissefoo.me/portfolio/the-art-of-memory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.me/portfolio/the-art-of-memory/</guid><description>What does it mean to remember? Sited in four Italian towns that have been indelibly changed by natural disasters, this project explores the notion of architectural memory. Across Pompeii, Catania, Poggioreale, and Gibellina, each town embodies a unique approach towards destruction and preservation. The ‘perfectly’ preserved ruins of Pompeii are set against the bustling capital of Catania, the ghost town of Poggioreale, and the crumbling modernist art installations of Gibellina.</description></item></channel></rss>