<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Charisse</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Charisse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charissefoo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Island Lodge Hotel Booking</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</guid><description>Overview The Challenge: Making hotel bookings on mobile should be quick and easy, but are often frustrating because of a lack of clarity, transparency, and trust.
The Goal: To design a mobile website with an intuitive and resassuring hotel booking process, allowing users to complete their booking in minutes.
My Role As part of my Professional Diploma in UX Design, I was responsible for all research, design, and prototyping. My earlier user research identified clarity, transparency, and trust as three main design goals in achieving a smoother hotel booking process.</description></item><item><title>The Island Lodge Research</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-research/</guid><description>Overview The Challenge: How can a mobile website for a hotel be best designed?
The Goal: To find out users&amp;rsquo; goals, behaviours, and pain points regarding making hotel bookings on mobile through in-depth user research
Research Methods Research methods include:
competitive analysis online survey usability tests interviews Findings were synthesised through affinity diagramming and presented in a customer journey map.
For the design outcome, please refer to The Island Lodge Hotel Booking case study.</description></item><item><title>SketchUp for Architecture</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/sketchup-for-architecture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/sketchup-for-architecture/</guid><description>A knowledge base for architects. Check it out here!
Why? SketchUp for Architecture was born from a desire to share knowledge.
It was started over a weekend while I was working full-time at an architectural office. With varying levels of experience within the firm, there was a great opportunity to share and establish best practices, streamline modelling processes, and essentially improve internal workflow for the team.
Architects do a lot.</description></item><item><title>Imaginary Worlds: An Introduction to 3D with Blender</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/teaching-blender/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/teaching-blender/</guid><description>The Result Check out the website for the two-day workshop, Imaginary Worlds: An Introduction to 3D with Blender, held in November 2022.
How it all began More than a decade ago, I chose to take Art as an A-Level subject.
In recent years, conversations with my junior college art teacher about art education and the role of technology in art-making led to some realisations:
3D software is largely absent from the art curriculum.</description></item><item><title>Magic Moving Mansion Mania</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</guid><description>Overview The Challenge: We had four months to make a mobile game. I was the Design Lead in a team of six: two designers and four programmers.
The Goal: To design and build a lovable mobile action-puzzle-platformer for iOS and Android.
Outcome Magic Moving Mansion Mania is a mobile action-puzzle-platformer for iOS and Android. It was conceptualised and created in four months under the Game Design Initiative at Cornell (GDIAC).</description></item><item><title>Establishing a Classical Pianist's Online Presence</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/pianist-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/pianist-website/</guid><description>Overview Clarisse, a classical pianist, was looking for ways to increase her online presence. I designed a website for her to consolidate her musical material in one place, and to establish her personal brand.
Existing Constraints Three barriers had prevented her from making a website herself: technical knowhow, cost, and time. She didn&amp;rsquo;t code, she was hesitant about committing to a hefty paid subscription, and, as a musician, she wanted to focus on making music.</description></item><item><title>Tyflow Experiments</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/tyflow-experiments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/tyflow-experiments/</guid><description>Experiments with 3D Physics and Particle Simulations I&amp;rsquo;d used 3DS Max professionally every day for a couple of years, but still barely scratched the surface of what it could do.
These experiments with Tyflow are by-products of deepening my technical and artistic skills, by learning more about 3D particle systems, physics simulations, and animation. I enrolled in the Tyflow Basecamp in 2020 and thoroughly enjoyed learning and making these.</description></item><item><title>Augmented Heritage Adventure (AHA!)</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/augmented-heritage-adventure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/augmented-heritage-adventure/</guid><description>Magical stories of talking animals, immortals, demons, and deities come to life through augmented reality. AHA! (Augmented Heritage Adventure) revives the famed Qing Dynasty work of Zichuan-born writer Pu Songling: Liaozhai Zhiyi (聊斋志异), known in English as Strange Tales from a Chinese Studio. Pu Songling’s residence in Zichuan has been preserved as a tourist attraction, and now his five hundred fantastic tales find new life in a gamified augmented reality adventure.</description></item><item><title>Oasis Waterpark</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/oasis-waterpark/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/oasis-waterpark/</guid><description>Oasis Waterpark explores architectural memory through comics. An illustrated journey through time and space, Oasis Waterpark tells of shared memories housed within one public playground. Each moment – joyful, familiar, comforting, playful, or poignant – is framed in a multi-panel comic, charting a narrative that contains the past, present, and future in the same place. This illustration pays homage to Frank King&amp;rsquo;s multi-panel comics of the 1930s, exploring the notion of place, imbued with meaning and memory, through the stories it contains: the structures in which we lose and find ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Satellite Town</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/satellite-town/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/satellite-town/</guid><description>Satellite Town illustrates a future of ecological living beyond the limits of the Earth. In a research community living in a satellite orbiting the Moon, distinct notions of self-sufficiency and sustainability are explored, each with a distinct color palette. The Forest depicts the distinctive pink glow of high intensity LEDs for crop growth; The Street imagines an underpass with bioluminescent mycelium pavements that generate electricity from footsteps; The Chapel depicts a zero-gravity projection room featuring an endless sunset against distant planets.</description></item><item><title>The Monument to the Labors</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-monument-to-the-labors/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-monument-to-the-labors/</guid><description>The Monument to the Labors tells an architectural fable in outer space. Narrated dispassionately, The Monument to the Labors imagines a future that has already been translated into history. In this recasting of the pioneer narrative, the first settlers of space are not merely brave explorers but also condemned convicts. Centering around alienation and the implications of denying humanity to the other, the story simultaneously charts the lifespan of a building: a satellite, prison, laboratory, factory, town, tomb, billboard, attraction, and symbol.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Memory</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-art-of-memory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-art-of-memory/</guid><description>Overview Historic preservation is often a dry topic, with a large focus on regulations and conservation. Here, we take an experimental approach towards preservation, investigating architectural memory through travel, documentation, and speculative drawings.
The Art of Memory was a collaboration with Yichen Jia, made possible by the 2018-2019 Robert James Eidlitz Travel Fellowship. It was exhibited in NYC and MIT, and published in book form.
What does it mean to remember?</description></item><item><title>Fluid Pavilion</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/fluid-pavilion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/fluid-pavilion/</guid><description>What does structural memory look like? An ethereal presence, Fluid Pavilion displays the ability of plastic to be both rigid and organic, with the lightness of a transparent enclosure. Built upon spatial, material, and visual deformations, the pavilion is both clear and hazy, open and closed: as much a window frame as it is a wall.
Fluid Pavilion was a collaboration with Hanxi Wang, with the mentorship of Sasa Zivkovic and Martin Miller, Cornell University.</description></item></channel></rss>