<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools &amp; Teaching on Charisse</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/categories/tools--teaching/</link><description>Recent content in Tools &amp; Teaching on Charisse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charissefoo.github.io/categories/tools--teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Imaginary Worlds: A Blender Workshop</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/teaching-blender/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/teaching-blender/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-result">The Result&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Check out the website for the two-day workshop, &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/view/imaginaryworlds">Imaginary Worlds: An Introduction to 3D with Blender&lt;/a>, held in November 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-it-all-began">How it all began&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>More than a decade ago, I chose to take Art as an A-Level subject.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, conversations with my junior college art teacher about &lt;strong>art education&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>the role of technology in art-making&lt;/strong> led to some realisations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>3D software is largely absent from the art curriculum.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Teachers aren&amp;rsquo;t really familiar with 3D software or what it can do.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some students pick up Blender by themselves and make artwork despite a steep learning curve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>As a graduate of that same art curriculum, I felt uniquely positioned to contribute. &lt;strong>I loved my time studying art&lt;/strong>, with all its opportunities for critical thought and developing a personal artistic practice. I also loved the possibilities - how much could be done, and how easily - opened by the knowledge of specific software, techniques, and workflows. The goal was not to merely &lt;em>teach Blender&lt;/em>, it was also to provide &lt;strong>a conceptual framework to approach computer-generated imagery (CGI) as a medium&lt;/strong>, and to eventually make thoughtful, sensitive artwork with it. With the digital world becoming increasingly important to all fields, it&amp;rsquo;d help to equip students with a basic understanding of virtual 3D space, its rules, and common operations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SketchUp for Architecture</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/sketchup-for-architecture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/sketchup-for-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-knowledge-base-for-architects">A knowledge base for architects.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/view/sketchupforarchitecture">Check it out here!&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why">Why?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SketchUp for Architecture was born from a desire to share knowledge.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was started over a weekend while I was working full-time at an architectural office. With varying levels of experience within the firm, there was a great opportunity to share and establish best practices, streamline modelling processes, and essentially improve internal workflow for the team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Architects do a lot.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>