<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UX Design on Charisse</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/tags/ux-design/</link><description>Recent content in UX Design on Charisse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charissefoo.github.io/tags/ux-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Island Lodge</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</guid><description>My Role As part of my Professional Diploma in UX Design, I was responsible for all research, design, and prototyping. My earlier user research identified clarity, transparency, and trust as three main design goals in achieving a smoother hotel booking process.
Deliverables The final product is a mobile website for The Island Lodge, a proposed luxury beachfront resort located on St John&amp;rsquo;s Island, Singapore.
Figma prototype (high fidelity &amp;amp; medium fidelity) Wireframes (high fidelity &amp;amp; medium fidelity) Handover documentation: high fidelity annotations User flow diagram Sketches For a more complete overview of the research process, please refer to the research case study.</description></item><item><title>Magic Moving Mansion Mania</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</guid><description>Overview Anastasia is lost in a magical mansion where the rooms move in mysterious ways. Help guide her to safety, but don’t let her fall into nothingness!
Magic Moving Mansion Mania is a mobile action-puzzle-platformer for iOS and Android. It was conceptualised and created in four months under the Game Design Initiative at Cornell (GDIAC).
Role I was the Design Lead in a team of six: two designers and four programmers.</description></item></channel></rss>