<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UX Research on Charisse</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/tags/ux-research/</link><description>Recent content in UX Research on Charisse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charissefoo.github.io/tags/ux-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Island Lodge</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</guid><description>Overview Role As part of my Professional Diploma in UX Design, I designed a mobile website focusing on the hotel booking process.
I was responsible for all research, design, and prototyping.
Context The Island Lodge is a proposed luxury beachfront resort located on St John&amp;rsquo;s Island, Singapore. Imagined as a redevelopment of the four existing campsites on the island, The Island Lodge offers a quieter alternative to the touristic holiday island of Sentosa.</description></item><item><title>The Island Lodge Research</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-research/</guid><description>Overview As part of my Professional Diploma in UX Design, I conducted research about the hotel booking process on mobile.
Research Deliverables Research methods include competitive analysis, an online survey, usability tests, and interviews Findings were synthesised through affinity diagramming and presented in a customer journey map.
For the design outcome, please refer to The Island Lodge Hotel Booking case study.
Online Survey To understand users&amp;rsquo; goals, behaviours, and pain points regarding the online hotel booking process, I conducted an online survey with family and friends.</description></item></channel></rss>