<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>project on Charisse</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/categories/project/</link><description>Recent content in project on Charisse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charissefoo.github.io/categories/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Island Lodge</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-hotel-booking/</guid><description>Overview Role As part of my Professional Diploma in UX Design, I designed a mobile website focusing on the hotel booking process.
I was responsible for all research, design, and prototyping.
Context The Island Lodge is a proposed luxury beachfront resort located on St John&amp;rsquo;s Island, Singapore. Imagined as a redevelopment of the four existing campsites on the island, The Island Lodge offers a quieter alternative to the touristic holiday island of Sentosa.</description></item><item><title>The Island Lodge Research</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/island-lodge-research/</guid><description>Overview As part of my Professional Diploma in UX Design, I conducted research about the hotel booking process on mobile.
Research Deliverables Research methods include competitive analysis, an online survey, usability tests, and interviews Findings were synthesised through affinity diagramming and presented in a customer journey map.
For the design outcome, please refer to The Island Lodge Hotel Booking case study.
Online Survey To understand users&amp;rsquo; goals, behaviours, and pain points regarding the online hotel booking process, I conducted an online survey with family and friends.</description></item><item><title>Augmented Heritage Adventure (AHA!)</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/augmented-heritage-adventure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/augmented-heritage-adventure/</guid><description>Magical stories of talking animals, immortals, demons, and deities come to life through augmented reality. AHA! (Augmented Heritage Adventure) revives the famed Qing Dynasty work of Zichuan-born writer Pu Songling: Liaozhai Zhiyi (聊斋志异), known in English as Strange Tales from a Chinese Studio. Pu Songling’s residence in Zichuan has been preserved as a tourist attraction, and now his five hundred fantastic tales find new life in a gamified augmented reality adventure.</description></item><item><title>Oasis Waterpark</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/oasis-waterpark/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/oasis-waterpark/</guid><description>Oasis Waterpark explores architectural memory through comics. An illustrated journey through time and space, Oasis Waterpark tells of shared memories housed within one public playground. Each moment – joyful, familiar, comforting, playful, or poignant – is framed in a multi-panel comic, charting a narrative that contains the past, present, and future in the same place. This illustration pays homage to Frank King&amp;rsquo;s multi-panel comics of the 1930s, exploring the notion of place, imbued with meaning and memory, through the stories it contains: the structures in which we lose and find ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Satellite Town</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/satellite-town/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/satellite-town/</guid><description>Satellite Town illustrates a future of ecological living beyond the limits of the Earth. In a research community living in a satellite orbiting the Moon, distinct notions of self-sufficiency and sustainability are explored, each with a distinct color palette. The Forest depicts the distinctive pink glow of high intensity LEDs for crop growth; The Street imagines an underpass with bioluminescent mycelium pavements that generate electricity from footsteps; The Chapel depicts a zero-gravity projection room featuring an endless sunset against distant planets.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Memory</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/the-art-of-memory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/the-art-of-memory/</guid><description>What does it mean to remember? Sited in four Italian towns that have been indelibly changed by natural disasters, this project explores the notion of architectural memory. Across Pompeii, Catania, Poggioreale, and Gibellina, each town embodies a unique approach towards destruction and preservation. The ‘perfectly’ preserved ruins of Pompeii are set against the bustling capital of Catania, the ghost town of Poggioreale, and the crumbling modernist art installations of Gibellina.</description></item><item><title>Magic Moving Mansion Mania</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</guid><description>Anastasia is lost in a magical mansion where the rooms move in mysterious ways. Help guide her to safety, but don’t let her fall into nothingness!
Overview Magic Moving Mansion Mania is a mobile action-puzzle-platformer for iOS and Android. It was conceptualised and created in four months under the Game Design Initiative at Cornell (GDIAC).
Role I was the Design Lead in a team of six: two designers and four programmers.</description></item><item><title>The Monument to the Labors</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-monument-to-the-labors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-monument-to-the-labors/</guid><description>The Monument to the Labors tells an architectural fable in outer space. Narrated dispassionately, The Monument to the Labors imagines a future that has already been translated into history. In this recasting of the pioneer narrative, the first settlers of space are not merely brave explorers but also condemned convicts. Centering around alienation and the implications of denying humanity to the other, the story simultaneously charts the lifespan of a building: a satellite, prison, laboratory, factory, town, tomb, billboard, attraction, and symbol.</description></item><item><title>Fluid Pavilion</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/fluid-pavilion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/fluid-pavilion/</guid><description>What does structural memory look like? An ethereal presence, Fluid Pavilion displays the ability of plastic to be both rigid and organic, with the lightness of a transparent enclosure. Built upon spatial, material, and visual deformations, the pavilion is both clear and hazy, open and closed: as much a window frame as it is a wall.
Fluid Pavilion was a collaboration with Hanxi Wang, with the mentorship of Sasa Zivkovic and Martin Miller, Cornell University.</description></item></channel></rss>