<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>collaboration on Charisse</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/tags/collaboration/</link><description>Recent content in collaboration on Charisse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charissefoo.github.io/tags/collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Magic Moving Mansion Mania</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/portfolio/magic-moving-mansion-mania/</guid><description>Overview The Challenge: We had four months to make a mobile game. I was the Design Lead in a team of six: two designers and four programmers.
The Goal: To design and build a lovable mobile action-puzzle-platformer for iOS and Android.
Outcome Magic Moving Mansion Mania is a mobile action-puzzle-platformer for iOS and Android. It was conceptualised and created in four months under the Game Design Initiative at Cornell (GDIAC).</description></item><item><title>Augmented Heritage Adventure (AHA!)</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/augmented-heritage-adventure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/augmented-heritage-adventure/</guid><description>Magical stories of talking animals, immortals, demons, and deities come to life through augmented reality. AHA! (Augmented Heritage Adventure) revives the famed Qing Dynasty work of Zichuan-born writer Pu Songling: Liaozhai Zhiyi (聊斋志异), known in English as Strange Tales from a Chinese Studio. Pu Songling’s residence in Zichuan has been preserved as a tourist attraction, and now his five hundred fantastic tales find new life in a gamified augmented reality adventure.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Memory</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-art-of-memory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/the-art-of-memory/</guid><description>Overview Historic preservation is often a dry topic, with a large focus on regulations and conservation. Here, we take an experimental approach towards preservation, investigating architectural memory through travel, documentation, and speculative drawings.
The Art of Memory was a collaboration with Yichen Jia, made possible by the 2018-2019 Robert James Eidlitz Travel Fellowship. It was exhibited in NYC and MIT, and published in book form.
What does it mean to remember?</description></item><item><title>Fluid Pavilion</title><link>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/fluid-pavilion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charissefoo.github.io/blog/fluid-pavilion/</guid><description>What does structural memory look like? An ethereal presence, Fluid Pavilion displays the ability of plastic to be both rigid and organic, with the lightness of a transparent enclosure. Built upon spatial, material, and visual deformations, the pavilion is both clear and hazy, open and closed: as much a window frame as it is a wall.
Fluid Pavilion was a collaboration with Hanxi Wang, with the mentorship of Sasa Zivkovic and Martin Miller, Cornell University.</description></item></channel></rss>